Catalog of the Walt Whitman Literary Manuscripts in The Charles E. Feinberg Collection of the Papers of Walt Whitman, 1839-1919, Library of Congress, Washington, DC.
Published by The Walt Whitman Archive in collaboration with the University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries.
- Literary File, 1841-1919, undated (Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37)
  - After the Supper and Talk, about 1887; loc.00175; xxx.00376; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf 12 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder After the Supper and talk (1887). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof of After the Supper and Talk, with corrections (all punctuation) in ink and two words written in purple pencil: "30 Copies." This poem was published first in 1887.
  - After Twenty Years, about 1888; loc.00176; xxx.00365; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 18.5 x 15.5 cm (Box 26, Folder After Twenty Years (1888). Proof Sheets.)
    Written in ink at the top of a proof of After Twenty Years, are six words: "From the English Magazine of Art." This poem was published under the title Twenty Years in 1888.
  - Ah, Not This Granite Dead and Cold, about 1885; loc.00067; xxx.00343; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 24.5 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder Ah, Not This Granite Dead and Cold (1885). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof with Whitman's holograph corrections. Published first under this title in 1885. Later published as Washington's Monument, February, 1885.
  - America, undated; loc.00006; xxx.00624; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 18.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 26, Folder America (1888). A.MS. Draft.)
    Despite the title, this manuscript does not appear to be a draft of the poem, America, published in 1888, but it has been published separately and posthumously as [America] and begins "No Homer, Shakspere, Voltaire." This manuscript was likely composed in the last two decades of Whitman's career (roughly 1870-1892 ) when he was more apt to mention other writers explicitly in his poetry.
  - America to Old World Bards, 1890-1891; loc.00047; xxx.00395; poetry handwritten 6 leaves (Box 26, Folder America to Old World Bards (1891). A.MS. drafts.)
    Written in ink on the inside of four discarded envelopes, one letter, and a sheet made by pasting together the insides of three discarded envelopes (all sent to Whitman in September and October 1890 ), entitled America to Old-World Bards: A reminiscence from reading Walter Scott, published as Old Chants in 1891.
  - As in a Swoon, about 1876; loc.00177; xxx.00567; poetry prose printed handwritten 1 leaf 6.5 x 12.5 cm (Box 26, Folder As In A Swoon. Proof.)
    A proof pasted on another sheet of paper, with seven words in Whitman's hand: "Walt Whitman, (discarded from last booklet.)" As in a Swoon was published first in 1876.
  - As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors, May 15, 1885; loc.00178; xxx.00341; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 54.5 x 36 cm (Folder As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors (1885). Printed Copy—Camden Post, May 15, 1885., Box 26)
    A page of The Post, Camden, N.J., 15 May 1885. Written in pencil in the margin at the top of front page are five words in Whitman's hand: "As one by one Withdraw." The Library of Congress's description of the item mentions that page three of the newspaper includes a reprint from Harper's Weekly of As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors; however, only one page of the newspaper is currently in the folder. As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors was later published as Death of General Grant.
  - As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors, about 1885; loc.00179; xxx.00341; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 16.5 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors. Proof Sheets.)
    Written in pencil at the bottom of a proof of As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors, a thirteen-line poem on President Grant's death, with a printed signature, four words: "Harper's Weekly, May 16." On the verso in another hand is "tr Nov 20 1885 ." Pasted on the verso is a small piece of paper, 5.25 x 10.75 cm, on which is written: "This fragment of Whitman's, Mr. (John) Burroughs sent me recently, with a lot of old papers & letters. As it has a memorandum in WW's hand, I know you will like to have it. C(lara).B(arrus)." This poem, published first in 1885, was also published as Death of General Grant.
  - As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors, about 1885; loc.00180; xxx.00341; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 26, Folder As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors. Proof Sheets.)
    Signed proof of the thirteen-line poem, As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors, first published in 1885, later published as Death of General Grant.
  - As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors, about 1885; loc.00492; xxx.00341; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 26, Folder As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors. Proof Sheets.)
    Annotated proof of the thirteen-line poem, As One by One Withdraw the Lofty Actors, first published in 1885, later published as Death of General Grant. This proof includes a notation suggesting the printed signature be moved to the left and that three words, "in Harper's Weekly," be inserted.
  - As the Greek's Signal Flame, about 1887; loc.00493; xxx.00371; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf 12 x 15.25 cm (Box 26, Folder As The Greek's Signal Flame (1887). Proof Sheets.)
    At the top of a proof of As the Greek's Signal Flame are nine words: "If convenient put in paper of Saturday Dec. 17."
  - Ashes of Roses, about 1870; loc.00050; xxx.00293; poetry handwritten 2 leaves 23.5 x 13.5 and 10 x 13.5 cm (Box 26, Folder Ashes of Roses. A.MS. drafts and notes.)
    Poem draft, parts of which have been printed as ? Ashes of Roses. The manuscript may bear a relationship to Ashes of Soldiers, a poem published first in 1865 as Hymn of Dead Soldiers in Drum-Taps. It was only in 1871 that Whitman added the imagery of ashes to this poem. The manuscript was likely composed around 1870-1871, when Whitman was revising and expanding the poem for republication. Alternatively, the manuscript may be a draft of a unique poetic work unpublished in Whitman's lifetime.
  - Autumn Rivulets, about 1881; loc.00181; xxx.00224; poetry 1 leaf handwritten (Box 26, Folder Autumn Rivulets (1881). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof of As Consequent, Etc., with cancelled title. This proof is housed at the Library of Congress with another, similarly marked, proof of As Consequent, Etc. (Whitman Archive ID: loc.00494) and unmarked proofs of the following poems: From Far Dakota's Cañons, A Farm Picture, What Best I See on Thee (U.S. Grant), The Sobbing of the Bells, Italian Music in Dakota, By Broad Potomac's Shore, Excelsior, With All thy Gifts, To Rich Givers, The Dalliance of the Eagles, Tears, After the Sea-Ship, Aboard at a Ship's Helm, and Thick-Sprinkled Bunting. As Consequent, Etc. was published first in 1881.
  - Autumn Rivulets, about 1881; loc.00494; xxx.00224; poetry 1 leaf handwritten (Box 26, Folder Autumn Rivulets (1881). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof of As Consequent, Etc., with cancelled title. This proof is housed at the Library of Congress with another, similarly marked, proof of As Consequent, Etc. (Whitman Archive ID: loc.00181) and unmarked proofs of the following poems: From Far Dakota's Cañons, A Farm Picture, What Best I See on Thee (U.S. Grant), The Sobbing of the Bells, Italian Music in Dakota, By Broad Potomac's Shore, Excelsior, With All thy Gifts, To Rich Givers, The Dalliance of the Eagles, Tears, After the Sea-Ship, Aboard at a Ship's Helm, and Thick-Sprinkled Bunting. As Consequent, Etc. was published first in 1881.
  - [Beat! Beat! Drums!], 1860-1865; loc.00051; xxx.00175; xxx.00606; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 26, Folder Beat! Beat! Drums! (1861). A. MS. draft.)
    On the recto is a draft of the first stanza of Beat! Beat! Drums! The poem first published simultaneously in Harper's Weekly and in the New York Leader on September 28, 1861. On the verso are lines on the death of President Lincoln, known as [Thou West that gave'st him to us] and first published in a Facsimile Edition of Drum-Taps in 1959.
  - [sorrow], about 1865; loc.00052; xxx.00217; poetry handwritten 2 leaves (Box 26, Folder Beat! Beat! Drums! (1861). A. MS. draft.)
    A list of about ninety words expressing sorrow. These words were evidently used as Whitman composed When Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom'd, first published in 1865.
  - [Ashes of ? soldiers heroes], about 1871; loc.00054; xxx.00293; poetry handwritten 2 leaves (Box 26, Folder Beat! Beat! Drums! (1861). A. MS. draft.)
    Draft of lines which bear a relationship to Ashes of Soldiers, first published in 1865. This manuscript was likely composed around 1870-1871, when Whitman was revising and expanding the poem for republication. This manuscript appears to be a draft of the first two linegroups of Ashes of Soldiers. These linegroups were added in 1871 to a poem first published as Hymn of Dead Soldiers in Drum-Taps ( 1865 ). It was only in 1871 that he added the imagery of ashes to this poem.
  - Bravo, Paris Exhibition!, about 1889; loc.00056; xxx.00392; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 21 x 27.5 cm (Box 26, Folder Bravo, Paris Exposition! (1889). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft of the poem published as Bravo, Paris Exposition! in 1889, with a diagonal line striking through the entire page.
  - Bravo, Paris Exhibition!, about 1889; loc.00057; xxx.00392; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 21 x 27.5 cm (Box 26, Folder Bravo, Paris Exposition! (1889). A.MS. drafts.)
    Signed draft of a poem with a variation in line 1 from the printed version. On the verso, written in pencil: "Can you use this? Put it under the "Personal" head like you did a year ago? "The price is $10, which please send me by mail here." In ink is the start of another sentence: "If you don't want it." The poem was published under the title Bravo, Paris Exposition! in 1889.
  - Bravo, Paris Exposition!, about 1889; loc.00058; xxx.00392; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 11.5 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder Bravo, Paris Exposition! (1889). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof sheet of Bravo, Paris Exposition! with corrections in Whitman's hand. Bravo, Paris Exposition! was published in 1889.
  - Bravo, Paris Exposition!, about 1889; loc.00059; xxx.00392; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 11.5 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder Bravo, Paris Exposition! (1889). Proof Sheets.)
  - Bravo, Paris Exposition!, about 1889; loc.00060; xxx.00392; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 11.5 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder Bravo, Paris Exposition! (1889). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof sheet of Bravo, Paris Exposition! with corrections in Whitman's hand. At the top is a note reading "See notes, Oct 31, '89 ." Bravo, Paris Exposition! was published in 1889.
  - Bravo, Paris Exposition!, about 1889; loc.00061; xxx.00392; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 26, Folder Bravo, Paris Exposition! (1889). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof sheet of Bravo, Paris Exposition! with corrections in Whitman's hand. At the top is a note in Traubel's hand: "Rec'd from W.W. Sept 30, '89 ". Bravo, Paris Exposition! was published in 1889.
  - The Buried Army, about 1885; loc.00108; xxx.00398; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 18 x 16 cm (Box 26, Folder The Buried Army (After Sept. 1885). A.MS. draft.)
    Trial lines, possibly for A Twilight Song, first published in 1890 and subtitled "For unknown buried soldiers, North and South."
  - [By day the distant], October, 1883; loc.00009; xxx.00340; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 17 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder By Day the Distant Shadowy Sails (1883). A.MS. draft.)
    Lines that likely constitute an early draft of With Husky-Haughty Lips, O Sea! This poem was published first in Harper's Monthly Magazine, March, 1884.
  - By Thine Own Lips, O Sea, about 1884; loc.00012; xxx.00340; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 26 x 20.5 cm (Box 26, Folder By Thine Own Lips, O Sea (1883). A.MS. draft.)
    An early draft of With Husky-Haughty Lips, O Sea! The poem was published in Harper's Monthly, March, 1884,
  - [Carols at Seventy], about 1888; loc.00016; xxx.00315; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 19.5 x 24 cm (Box 26, Folder A Carol Closing Sixty-Nine (1888). Proof Sheets and note.)
    Several trial titles for "A Carol Closing Sixty-Nine," first published in the New York Herald on 21 May 1888 and reprinted in the "Sands at Seventy" annex to Leaves of Grass the same year.
  - Certainties, Faith, Counterbalances, Alternation, between 1882-1888; loc.00075; xxx.00349; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 25 x 20 cm (Box 26, Folder Certainties, Faith, Counterbalances, Alternation. A.MS. draft.)
    Written in ink on the verso of a discarded letter (cancelled by a diagonal strike) from Talcott Williams, this draft appears to be trial lines for the poem later published as Continuities in the New York Herald, March 20, 1888.
  - [I do not relegate you], between 1850-1860; loc.00035; xxx.00784; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 26.5 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder Children of Adam. A.MS. draft.)
    These lines have an unknown relationship to Whitman's published work.
  - [Power, passions, vehement joys], between 1850-1860; loc.00036; xxx.00783; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 26.5 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder Children of Adam. A.MS. draft.)
  - [Yet completion were lacking if], between 1850-1860; loc.00037; xxx.00053; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 26.5 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder Children of Adam. A.MS. draft.)
    This manuscript contains a line used in Poem of Procreation in 1856 (later known as A Woman Waits for Me).
  - [Through you I drain the pent-up of rivers], between 1850 and 1860; loc.00038; xxx.00053; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 26.5 x 15 cm
    This manuscript contains lines that later appeared in Poem of Procreation in 1856 (later known as A Woman Waits for Me).
  - [Two scenes capriciously rising out of the past], between 1850-1860; loc.00039; xxx.00614; xxx.00789; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 26.5 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder Children of Adam. A.MS. draft.)
    Portions appear to be trial lines for a poem entitled Pictures published posthumously, first in 1925. Other lines have an unknown relationship to Whitman's published work.
  - A Christmas Greeting, about 1889; loc.00007; xxx.00396; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20 x 23.5 cm (Box 26, Folder A Christmas Greeting (1889). A.MS. drafts.)
    This manuscript of A Christmas Greeting was apparently intended for the printer, as there are few alterations. In right hand corner is notation in red: "if convenient let me have proof by noon." In left hand corner (in pencil) is the name "Horace Traubel." The poem was first published in 1889.
  - [A North Star], about 1889; loc.00008; xxx.00396; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 18 x 20.5 cm (Box 26, Folder A Christmas Greeting (1889). A.MS. drafts.)
    Written in pencil on a tan piece of paper cut from a larger sheet, 130 words with the title A North Star [page torn] South. The poem was later revised and titled A Christmas Greeting ( 1889 ).
  - A Christmas Greeting, about 1889; loc.00010; xxx.00396; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf 13.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 26, Folder A Christmas Greeting (1889). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof of A Christmas Greeting with several corrections.
  - A Christmas Greeting, about 1889; loc.00011; xxx.00396; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 13.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 26, Folder A Christmas Greeting (1889). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof with three emendations and a notation by Horace Traubel: "See notes 1/29/90 ."
  - A Clear Midnight, about 1880; loc.00062; xxx.00291; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf 19.5 x 14.5 cm (Box 26, Folder A Clear Midnight (1881). A.MS. Draft.)
    A draft of A Clear Midnight, written on the back of a letter from "A. Williams" dated December 2, 1880. The poem was first published in 1881.
  - Come, Said My Soul, 1881; loc.00183; xxx.00596; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 26, Folder Come, said my Soul… Proof with signature.)
    Signed proof page with no annotations. On verso reads "Copyright 1881, By Walt Whitman, All rights reserved"
  - The Commonplace, about 1890; loc.00076; xxx.00403; xxx.00400; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 27 x 19 cm (Box 26, Folder The Commonplace (1891). A.MS. draft.)
    On one side is a draft of The Commonplace, which was first published in manuscript facsimile in 1891. On the other side is a cancelled early draft of Osceola, a poem first published in 1890.
  - The Commonplace, March, 1891; loc.04077; xxx.00403; poetry 1 leaf (Box 26, Folder The Commonplace (Mar. 1891). Printed Copy.)
    A copy of the March, 1891, issue of Munson's Magazine, which includes, in manuscript facsimile, The Commonplace.
  - The Dalliance of the Eagles, about 1880; loc.00023; xxx.00155; poetry handwritten 4 leaves 21.5 x 20 cm (Box 26, Folder The Dalliance of the Eagles (1880). A.MS. drafts.)
    On a surface made by pasting together six scraps of paper (back of a discarded envelope from Geo. S. Woodhull and Son, Law Offices, Camden, postmarked Apr 6; back of a discarded letter, dated New York, March 29, 1880; and other scraps), a late draft of the poem The Dalliance of the Eagles, about 120 words, showing a few minor variations from the first-published version of 1880.
  - [Skirting the river], 1880; loc.00132; xxx.00155; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 12.5 x 19 cm (Box 26, Folder The Dalliance of the Eagles (1880). A.MS. drafts.)
    These lines were later revised and published as The Dalliance of the Eagles in 1880.
  - The Dalliance of the Eagles, about 1880; loc.00184; xxx.00155; xxx.00117; xxx.00166; xxx.00259; xxx.00277; xxx.00257; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 25.8 x 18.6 cm (Box 26, Folder The Dalliance of the Eagles (1880). Proof Sheets.)
    Written in ink on a proof of The Dalliance of the Eagles, Ah, little knows the Laborer, Hast never come to thee an hour?, and My Picture-Gallery, are 14 words of notations in Whitman's hand. The proof has been pasted to a heavy piece of paper, on the verso of which is A Riddle Song, part of Italian Music in Dakota, and a clipped headline reading "The Society Articles Save Labor. Lighten the Labor for Mother."
  - The Dead Tenor, about 1884; loc.00185; xxx.00348; poetry prose handwritten 2 leaves 24 x 15 cm, 10.5 x 16.5 cm (Box 26, Folder The Dead Tenor (1884). Proof Sheets.)
    Written in pencil on a small page from a notebook, on which is pasted a clipping from a newspaper about the funeral of Signor Brignoli and the reaction of Patti, pinned to an unmarked proof of The Dead Tenor, thirty words: "I heard the earliest singing of Patti, (in 1860 if I remember right)—heard her many times, Brignoli sang with her at her first appearance in NY in 1859 ." The poem was first published in 1884.
  - The Dead Tenor, about 1884; loc.00186; xxx.00348; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 21 x 15 cm, 20.5 x 15.25 cm, 24.25 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder The Dead Tenor (1884). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof of The Dead Tenor, with notations and corrections in Whitman's hand. The poem was first published in 1884.
  - The Dead Tenor, about 1884; loc.00497; xxx.00348; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 21 x 15 cm, 20.5 x 15.25 cm, 24.25 x 15 cm (Box 26, Folder The Dead Tenor (1884). Proof Sheets.)
  - A Death-Bouquet, about 1890; loc.00187; xxx.00562; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 25 x 19.5 cm (Box 26, Folder A Death-Bouquet (1890). A.MS. draft.)
    A five-line draft of a poem, entitled A Death-Bouquet, which was never published and has an unknown relationship to Whitman's published work. A subtitle reads "Fresh pick'd noon time early January, 1890, By Walt Whitman." These lines bear some relation to Whitman's brief essay of the same name.
  - Death Dogs My Steps, about March 3, 1890; loc.00120; xxx.00406; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 12 x 19 cm (Box 26, Folder Death Dogs My Steps (1890). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft of Death Dogs My Steps written in ink on the inside of a discarded and opened out envelope, addressed to Whitman from England, mailed in London February 21, 1890 and postmarked received in Camden March 3, 1890. The three lines later appeared as part of L. of G.'s Purport, first published in 1891.
  - [Aye, well I know 'tis ghastly to descend], about 1889; loc.00107; xxx.00593; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 26, Folder Death's Valley (1889). A.MS. drafts and printed copies.)
    Eight lines evidently written originally as part of Death's Valley, which was published first in Harper's New Monthly Magazine in 1892. The stanza later was slightly revised and published as On the Same Picture (the title was probably supplied by Traubel) in 1897.
  - Death's Valley, about 1889; loc.00189; xxx.00593; poetry handwritten 4 leaves (Box 26, Folder Death's Valley (1889). A.MS. drafts and printed copies.)
    A heavily marked-up draft of Death's Valley, a poem requested by Harper's Magazine and submitted in 1889, but not published until 1892.
  - [Lay on the graves of all dead soldiers], undated; loc.00190; xxx.00731; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 21 x 21.5 cm (Box 26, Folder Decoration Day. A.MS. draft)
    Trial lines for a poem published posthumously as [Decoration Day], a phrase underlined near the bottom of the page. The lines bear a resemblance to Ashes of Soldiers, though that poem was published in 1865 and the United States did not declare Decoration Day an official holiday until 1868, suggesting that this manuscript was probably composed later. Notes in a hand other than Whitman's appear on the reverse.
  - The Dismantled Ship, about 1888; loc.00191; xxx.00372; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 26, Folder The Dismantled Ship (1888). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of The Dismantled Ship, first published in 1888, written on the inside of an opened envelope (postmark date unclear). At the bottom of the page in a note in Whitman's hand: "probably printed in Herald 19th Feb. '88 ."
  - Down, down, proud gorge, about 1889; loc.00192; xxx.00389; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 26, Folder Down, Down, Proud Gorge. A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of a poem titled Down, down, proud gorge. At the bottom of the same leaf is another draft of a poem entitled Are they last words? These drafts were later greatly revised and combined when published in 1889 with the title To the Year 1889, later re-titled To the Pending Year.
  - The Dying Veteran, June 23, 1887; loc.00193; xxx.00362; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 26, Folder The Dying Veteran (1887). A.MS. draft.)
    A dated, signed draft of The Dying Veteran, first published in 1887. A note at end reads: "Given to Thomas Mosher by Horace Traubel, 1900 ." On verso of the page is a note by Whitman to "Mr. Curtz" (type setter) asking for a finished proof by the middle of the afternoon, Wednesday.
  - [Each claim, ideal, line], about 1891; loc.00194; xxx.00406; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 26, Folder Each Claim, ideal, Line… A.MS. draft.)
    This draft appears to be trial lines for the poems L. of G.'s Purport and L of G, both published in 1891. Near the middle of the page appear three underlined words, "These pages past," but whether or not they were intended as a title is unclear.
  - Ebb and Flood Tides, undated; loc.00195; xxx.00732; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 15 x 24.25 cm (Box 26, Folder Ebb and Flood Tides A.MS. draft.)
    An unpublished poem written in ink on a pale tan piece of paper, heavily corrected.
  - [The Epos of a Life], undated; loc.00196; xxx.00733; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 13.75 x 20.5 cm (Box 26, Folder The Epos of a Life… A.MS. draft.)
    An unpublished poem written on a piece of lined stationery.
  - Fancies at Navesink, about 1885; loc.00327; xxx.00330; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 48 x 15 cm (Box 27, Folder Fancies at Navesink (1885). Proof Sheets.)